# **Curriculum Vitae**

## **Zack Ferro-Fields**

<u>zackferrofields@gmail.com</u> GitHub I Gists I GitPage

### **PROFILE**

Experienced software developer, building applications for multiple environments including web, native, hybrid and server. I'm currently pursuing my interests in isomorphic applications, functional reactive programming, unidirectional data flow, and the latest ECMAScript standards es2015 & es2016.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Lead Developer - Senior Software Engineer, The BIO Agency – FEB 2014 - PRESENT.

#### **Premium Credit Point of Purchase (PoP)**

PoP is a reactive event-driven web application with a <u>Flux</u> architecture, for creating & managing financed insurance premiums. The application was composed of asynchronous data streams using functional programming paradigms such as pure functions, function composition, higher order functions, immutable state, etc. The application was continuous integration & deployed with GitHub, Travis CI and Docker Cloud.

es2015, esNext, jsx, babel, RxJs, cssnext, postcss, tape, istanbul, node, docker, travis

#### **CHEP Better Portfolio**

myCHEP is a suite of mobile-first Backbone/Marionette applications. The project used Bower to manager 3rd party library dependencies (Marionette, Zepto, Lodash, Polyglot). Grunt for automated build processes (bundling modules, compiling SCSS, minification, concatenation, running unit-test, code-coverage, etc) and continuous-integration with Jenkins and Maven.

webpack, babel es2015, scss, backbone, marionette, lodash, karma, jasmine, jenkins, maven, tomcat

#### The BIO Agency website

thebioagency.com is a responsive isomorphic application written in javascript. The stack, dockernginx-react, uses anode server with koa APIs and an nginx proxy, to implement a "micro" cache with HTTP cahce-Control. The content was hosted on a separate upstream in GitHub as markdown and compiled to html.

#### **Sky Sports Soccer Quiz**

A node application using express to serve REST APIs for an Android/iPhone app and store data in a mongodatabase. The application was unit-tested with mocha (and chai BDD assertion) using sinon and superagent.

node, espress, mongodb, mocha, sinon, superagent

## Senior Front-End Developer, AIS London – MAY 2013 - FEB 2014.

**Dozenate:** An Android alarm clock with charity micro-payments. The application was built for Android 4.0+. The proof-of-concept involved building custom UI components including an analogue clock with draggable dials for setting alarms. The app used "Just Test Giving" to send micro-payments to charities via SMS.

## Developer, Skinkers / IMI Mobile – DEC 2011 - MAY 2013.

**Barclays Bikes:** An iOS and Android application for built using Titanium (Appcelerator). The appused real-time TFL data for locating bikes/docks and plotting the data on a map.

**Affiliate Window:** A portal for Affiliate Window users to view stats and manage their accounts. The app was built with Ember and bundled using Cordova, for Android and iOS app stores.

**Red Bull Racing Spy:** An iOS app built with Titanium (Appcelerator) that aggregated Red Bull Raging content/feeds (Tumblr, Twitter, Facebook)

# Software Engineer, Grapple Mobile – JUN 2010 - DEC 2011.

Building mobile applications, with a single source (JavaScript, HTML and CSS) compiled to multiple platforms (iOS, Android Blackberry/J2ME) for clients including Microsoft, Pfizer, T-Mobile and Premier Inn.

# **EDUCATION**

**Southampton Solent University – 2007 - 2010.** 

**Upper Second BSC (Hons) Software Engineering**